<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Matching Engine on OH! THO</title><link>https://www.nktho.fr/tags/matching-engine/</link><description>Recent content in Matching Engine on OH! THO</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.nktho.fr/tags/matching-engine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Stock Exchange</title><link>https://www.nktho.fr/p/trading_exchange/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.nktho.fr/p/trading_exchange/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://www.nktho.fr/p/trading_exchange/trading_exchange.webp" alt="Featured image of post Stock Exchange" />&lt;h3 id="1-architect">1. Architect&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The trading exchange is designed with a modular architecture that enhances its performance and scalability.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="2-server">2. Server&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The server serves as the backbone of the trading exchange, utilizing the &lt;strong>UDP (User Datagram Protocol)&lt;/strong> for communication. This protocol is selected for its low-latency characteristics, essential in trading environments where every millisecond matters. However, it&amp;rsquo;s important to note that UDP can lead to packet loss, which may not be ideal for trading. As such, a future transition to &lt;strong>TCP (Transmission Control Protocol)&lt;/strong> is planned to ensure more reliable communication, providing guaranteed delivery of messages. The server efficiently processes incoming client requests and dispatches them to the matching engine.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Asynchronous Handling&lt;/strong>: Implemented using &lt;strong>Boost.Asio&lt;/strong>, the server can handle multiple requests concurrently without blocking, allowing it to serve numerous clients simultaneously while maintaining high responsiveness.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="21-matching-engine">2.1 Matching Engine&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The matching engine is the core component responsible for executing trades by matching buy and sell orders based on specific criteria. Its architecture includes several key features:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Multi-Orderbook Support&lt;/strong>: The engine supports multiple orderbooks, each corresponding to a different trading symbol (e.g., stock, commodity).&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>AtPriceOrderMap&lt;/strong>: This structure is designed to maintain orders with the same price. Each price level contains an &lt;code>AtPriceOrder&lt;/code> which groups orders that share the same price point. Orders are prioritized based on their submission time, ensuring fairness in execution.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Hashtable Utilization&lt;/strong>: By using a hashtable (implemented with &lt;code>std::array&lt;/code>), the matching engine achieves constant-time complexity for lookups, allowing for quick access to active orders.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Top of Book (TOB)&lt;/strong>: The engine maintains a &lt;code>Top of Book&lt;/code> (TOB) for both buy and sell sides, facilitating immediate access to the best available prices.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Buy Side TOB&lt;/strong>: Represents the highest buy price currently available. The next &lt;code>AtPriceOrder&lt;/code> in the sequence is the next highest order, ensuring that the market is transparent for buyers.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Sell Side TOB&lt;/strong>: Represents the lowest sell price, with the subsequent order being the next smallest price. This mechanism promotes competitive pricing in the market.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Order Management&lt;/strong>: The &lt;code>OrderManager&lt;/code> component is critical for managing the lifecycle of orders. It handles:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Order Creation&lt;/strong>: Facilitates the submission of new orders into the orderbook.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Order Expiry&lt;/strong>: Responsible for removing orders that are no longer valid (e.g., due to time constraints or market conditions).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="22-fifo-queue">2.2 FIFO Queue&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>To enable efficient communication between the server and the matching engine, a thread-safe &lt;strong>MPMC (Multi-Producers, Multi-Consumers)&lt;/strong> queue is utilized. This design allows multiple threads to produce and consume messages concurrently without risking data corruption.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Output Streaming&lt;/strong>:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Standard Output (Stdout)&lt;/strong>: Used for streaming results from the matching engine, ensuring that all output is managed in a thread-safe manner to prevent data races.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Standard Log (Stdlog)&lt;/strong>: Employed for logging performance metrics, allowing for detailed monitoring of system performance. Example log messages include:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;code>Perf|OrderBook|Add|Execution|111&lt;/code>: Indicates that an order was added, with an execution time of 111 milliseconds.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>Perf|OrderBook|Cancel|Execution|50&lt;/code>: Indicates that an order was canceled, with an execution time of 50 milliseconds.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="3-improvements">3. Improvements&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To enhance the functionality and performance of the trading exchange, several improvements are planned:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Protocol Support&lt;/strong>: Develop an interface for the server to support additional communication protocols, such as &lt;strong>TCP/IP&lt;/strong>. This would provide flexibility for clients to connect using various network protocols, improving usability.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>FIX Protocol Implementation&lt;/strong>: Integrate the &lt;strong>FIX (Financial Information eXchange)&lt;/strong> protocol, a standardized messaging protocol for the real-time exchange of securities transactions. This would enhance interoperability with other trading systems and brokers.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Lock-Free Queue Development&lt;/strong>: Create a &lt;strong>lock-free queue&lt;/strong> to minimize contention between threads. This would enhance performance in high-frequency trading scenarios where order flow can be extremely high.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Performance Optimization&lt;/strong>: Conduct performance profiling and optimization to identify bottlenecks within the system, ensuring that the exchange can handle increased loads efficiently.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Object Pool Implementation&lt;/strong>: Introduce an &lt;strong>object pool&lt;/strong> to manage the allocation and deallocation of objects. This technique reduces the overhead of dynamic memory allocations, leading to improved performance and reduced latency.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>By focusing on these enhancements, the trading exchange aims to deliver a robust, scalable, and high-performance platform that meets the demands of modern financial markets.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>